homedepotrebates.com 2012-11-13

# Customer Support: Privacy Security

We know that your privacy is very important to you. That's why protecting any personal information, such as your name, address, e-mail address or phone number that you provide to us is of the utmost importance to The Home Depot, Inc. and its subsidiaries, divisions, affiliates, brands and other The Home Depot companies ("[The Home Depot ](http://www.homedepot.com/webapp/catalog/servlet/HomePageView?storeId=10051&langId=-1&catalogId=10053)"). As a result, we have prepared this Privacy and Security Statement to let you know about the manner in which we collect, use, disclose and otherwise manage the personal information you entrust to us at any of our The Home Depot store locations (the "Stores"), through any The Home Depot Call Centers (the "Call Centers"), through The Home Depot websites (the "Sites"), or through our authorized service providers ("Service Providers").

When you provide personal information at our Stores, our Call Centers, our Sites and to our Service Providers, you are consenting to the manner in which The Home Depot will collect, use, disclose and otherwise manage your personal information, as set out below.

For purposes of this Privacy Statement, The Home Depot Canada, The Home Depot Mexico, and Home Decorators Collection are considered separate businesses. The Privacy Statements for these businesses may be viewed at [www.homedepot.ca/privacy](http://www.homedepot.ca/privacy), [www.homedepot.com.mx/privacy](http://www.homedepot.com.mx/wps/portal/homedepot/acerca/privacidad), and [www.homedecorators.com/privacy](http://www.homedecorators.com/privacy).

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

We may collect personal information that you provide us when you:

  * Purchase, order, return, exchange or request certain information about our products and services;
  * Request a quote and/or purchase one of our home services for your home or office;
  * Sign up or register for loyalty club membership communications or offerings;
  * Rent tools, equipment and/or trucks from one of our Stores;
  * Request warranty or product repair services;
  * Contact a Call Center or customer service desk;
  * Sign up for and/or register for a clinic or workshop;
  * Visit or register with our Sites or participate in another feature of our Sites, such as a bulletin board;
  * Enter into a contest or sweepstakes or respond to one of our surveys; or
  * Provide us with comments or suggestions.  

We may also collect personal information about you from our Service Providers.

**Shopping at The Home Depot:  **

When you purchase products and services at one of our Stores, you can do so anonymously when you pay with cash. If you use a credit or debit card for any of your purchases, we will collect your credit or debit card information and keep a history of your purchases. We use this information to process your orders, to ensure proper delivery, to better assist you when you visit or call us as well as to improve our product and service offerings.

When you return previously purchased merchandise or request a refund or exchange, you may be asked to give your name, address, phone number and show information that identifies you, such as your driver's license. We collect this information to help prevent fraud.

**Home Services and Tool Rentals:** When you purchase home services you will be asked for information such as your name, address, e-mail address and phone number. You may also be asked for your credit or debit card details along with a shipping or installation address. This information will help ensure the proper delivery of the services you order from The Home Depot and our Service Providers and to better assist you when you call us. For other services, such as truck rentals or certain equipment rentals, we may request that you present additional personal information and identification, such as a driver's license and verification of insurance.

**Call Centers:** When you call one of our Call Centers about a product, delivery, an installation, a billing question or for customer service, you may be asked for information that identifies you along with additional information we need to help us promptly answer your question, such as your name and address and a phone number where we might contact you. We may retain this information to assist you in the future.

**Online Registration:** Registration is an optional service provided by our Sites. You do not have to register to browse or shop online. When you register, you are asked for personal information such as your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, a password that you select, and optionally, your interests. Your registration information may be used to help make your online shopping quicker and easier, by pre-filling certain parts of your shopping information. When you register you will have the opportunity to sign up for future marketing information from The Home Depot.

**Contests, Questions or Surveys:** When you ask a question, participate in a survey or enter a contest or sweepstakes at a Store, a The Home Depot sponsored event or through our Sites, we may collect your name, address, phone number and e-mail address. We use this information to administer your participation in a contest or sweepstakes. At the time you are entering a contest or sweepstakes, we may ask your permission to send you future marketing information from The Home Depot.

**Other Uses of Personal Information:** The Home Depot uses personal information, including information provided to us from our Service Providers, to continually assess and improve the products and services we offer. We would also like to inform you of products and services, sales and special offers that might benefit you. When you register online or participate in a survey, you will have the opportunity to sign up for e-mails about our products, services, sales and special offers.

We may also send you mail, e-mail or call you with information about our product and service offerings if you have provided us with your name and address, e-mail address or phone numbers at our Stores, Call Centers or Sites. If you would like to stop receiving such promotional information from The Home Depot, please see the Privacy Preferences/Opt-Out section of this Privacy and Security Statement or go to [www.homedepot.com/privacypreferences](http://www.homedepot.com/webapp/catalog/servlet/ContentView?pn=Manage_Privacy_Preferences&storeId=10051&langId=-1&catalogId=10053) for further instructions on how to register your preferences.

**Privacy Preferences / Opt-Out:** We now offer an on-line privacy preference page at [www.homedepot.com/privacypreferences](http://www.homedepot.com/webapp/catalog/servlet/ContentView?pn=Manage_Privacy_Preferences&storeId=10051&langId=-1&catalogId=10053) where you can register or change your preferences to receive or not receive marketing materials sent by phone, e-mail and mail. You may update these preferences at any time. Please allow sufficient time for your preferences to be processed.

For purposes of this Privacy Statement, The Home Depot Canada, The Home Depot Mexico and Home Decorators Collection are considered separate businesses. If you have provided information directly to either of these businesses and want to register or change your preferences you must do so directly with that business. The Privacy Statements and privacy preference options for these businesses may be viewed at [www.homedepot.ca](http://www.homedepot.ca/), [www.homedepot.com.mx](http://www.homedepot.com.mx/) and[ www.homedecorators.com](http://www.homedecorators.com/).

**Information about Others:** At our Stores, Call Centers or on some of the pages on our Sites, you can submit information about other people and compose personalized messages to them. For example, you can order The Home Depot Gift Cards and merchandise and send them directly to a friend along with a personalized message composed by you. We consider the information you submit and the content of your personalized message to be a private communication between you and the recipient. The Home Depot will not use or disclose any information you provide about someone else for any purpose other than:

1\. To ship the order and confirm delivery;

2\. To identify or resolve technical problems or customer service issues;

3\. As required by law and to comply with a court order or other legal process;

4\. To respond to claims that your personalized messages violate the rights of third parties; and

5\. To protect the rights or property of The Home Depot and its affiliates

**Your Suggestions:** We use your feedback, suggestions, survey information and comments solely to monitor and/or improve the use and features of our Stores, Call Centers, our Sites and our product and service offerings.

**California Privacy Rights:**  Read full disclosure [here](http://www.homedepot.com/webapp/catalog/servlet/ContentView?pn=California_Privacy_Rights&storeId=10051&langId=-1&catalogId=10053).

**Protecting Childrens' Privacy:**

The Home Depot Sites are not intended for use by children under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 18.

More information for parents about our Kids Workshops can be obtained from your local Home Depot Store. We do not offer an online application for our Kids Workshops.

**Disclosure of Personal Information  **

**Personal Information Disclosure: The Home Depot will not trade, rent or sell your personal information, without your prior consent, except as otherwise set out herein.**

**The Home Depot Financial Products:** The Home Depot uses Service Providers to offer financial products, such as the The Home Depot credit card and home improvement loan. We may share personal information about The Home Depot consumers with these Service Providers in order to provide you with tailored information about products and services and special offers. These Service Providers also have their own privacy statement that sets out the manner in which they will collect, use and disclose personal information. We encourage you to review each Service Provider's privacy statement at the time you submit your application for such services.

**Extended Warranty Services:** If you purchase a The Home Depot Extended Warranty Service you will be required to provide information such as your name and address to our warranty Service Provider. While these Service Providers are limited by contract in the way they may use your information to provide The Home Depot Warranty Services, we encourage you to review the Service Provider's privacy statement at the time you submit your personal information for such services.

**Data Sharing for Catalog Mailings:** We may share your name, address and transactional information about products you have purchased from our catalogs with third party companies so that you may receive future catalog offerings about products and services that may be of interest to you. If you prefer not to have your information shared with third party companies for this purpose, please see the section above entitled Privacy Preferences/Opt-Out.

**Other Service:** In the U.S., to serve you better, we may combine the personal information that you give us on our Sites and at our Stores or through our catalogs with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with our marketing partners and others. We use that combined information to enhance and personalize your shopping experience with us, to communicate with you about our products and events that may be of interest to you, and for other promotional purposes.

**Companies that work with or on behalf of The Home Depot:** Some of our operations, such as our call centers, may be managed by unaffiliated companies. Also, if you purchase home services from The Home Depot, these services may not be provided by The Home Depot associates, but rather by reputable local or national companies with which we contract to provide such services. These companies may have access to your personal information on a confidential basis only to the extent necessary to perform their functions. In no event will these companies have the right to use your personal information for any reason other than to provide you with those specific services.  Information provided by you will be used by The Home Depot and its Service Providers to learn about the experiences of our customers so that we may enhance our programs and improve our level of service.

If your purchases are being shipped to you, we will share your shipping information on a confidential basis with our delivery service providers (U.S. Postal Service, Canada Post, or other delivery companies we or you select). Our delivery service providers are prohibited from using your personal information for any purpose other than making the delivery.

**Sale of Business:** The Home Depot reserves the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets to a third party acquirer.

**Legal:** Please note that The Home Depot must provide your personal information in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry or order, or to an investigative body in the case of a breach of an agreement or contravention of law, or as otherwise required by law. We may also disclose personal information to assist us in collecting a debt owed by you.

**Access to Personal Information**

You may request access to the personal information that we have about you. As a registered user with our Sites, you can access your profile information at any time by:

1\. Clicking on the "Sign In" button at the top of any page on the Sites on which you registered, then

2\. Clicking on the "Your Account" button on the page header or on the "Your Account" link under Customer Support.

For further instructions on accessing the personal information that The Home Depot may have about you, please see the How to Contact Us section of this Privacy and Security Statement.

**Additional Information about Our Sites**

**Visiting Our Sites** : In general, you can visit our Sites without telling us who you are or providing us with any information. However, we collect the IP (Internet protocol) addresses of all visitors to our Sites and other related information such as page requests, browser type, operating system and average time spent on our Sites. We use this information to monitor and improve our Sites.

**Cookies:** Our Sites use a technology called "cookies". A cookie is a tiny element of data that our Sites can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive so we can recognize you when you return. All pages on our Sites where you are prompted to log in or that are customizable require that you accept cookies. If you have registered with our Sites, these cookies (1) may let us know who you are, (2) are necessary to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver products and personalized services, and (3) will provide us and our service providers with information that we will use to personalize our Sites in accordance with your preferences. Cookies are also required to optimize your shopping experience in that they allow you to add multiple items to your shopping basket before checking out. You may set your Web browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. However, should you decide not to accept cookies from our Sites, you will limit the functionality we can provide when you visit our Sites.

**Tracer Tags:** Our Sites may also use a technology called "tracer tags". These may also be referred to as "Clear GIFs" or "Web Beacons". This technology allows us to understand which pages you visit on our Sites. These tracer tags are used to help us optimize and tailor our Sites for you and other future website visitors.

**Online Advertising:** We partner with third-party ad networks to deliver online advertising about our products and services when you visit our Sites or other websites on the Internet. These partnerships help us provide you with advertisements that are tailored to your particular interests, improve and optimize your experience on our Sites, and track the effectiveness of marketing efforts. To facilitate these online advertising efforts, our ad network partners may use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to collect information about your activities on our Sites or other websites. You can choose not to have your information collected for this purpose. To learn more about online advertising based on this form of information collection, including how you can opt out of such collection, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

**Third Party Links:** Our Sites may include links to the websites of our business partners, vendors and advertisers. Except as provided herein, we will not provide any of your personal information to these third parties without your prior consent.

The Home Depot provides links to third party websites as a convenience to the user. The inclusion of any link does not imply The Home Depot's endorsement of any other company, its websites, or its products and/or services. These linked websites have separate and independent privacy policies, which we recommend that you read carefully. We have no control over such websites and therefore have no responsibility or liability for the manner in which the organizations that operate such linked websites may collect, use or disclose and otherwise treat your personal information.

**Security of Personal Information**

We will maintain the confidentiality of all personal information collected in our Stores, our Call Centers, our Sites and from our Service Providers and will only disclose such information to employees and Service Providers who require such information for the purposes described in this Privacy and Security Statement. We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure of personal information in our custody and control.

**Security Measures on Our Sites**

**Secure Shopping:** When you place orders on our Sites, all of your order information, including your card number and delivery address, is transmitted through the Internet using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. SSL technology causes your browser to encrypt your order information before transmitting it to our secure server. SSL technology, an industry standard, is designed to prevent someone other than operators of our Sites from capturing and viewing your personal information.

The Home Depot also takes the following measures to protect your personal information online:

**Passwords:** To provide you with an increased level of security, online access to your personal information is protected with a password you select. We strongly recommend that you do not disclose your password to anyone. The Home Depot will never ask you for your password in any unsolicited communication (including unsolicited correspondence such as letters, phone calls or e-mail messages).

**Order Information** : Since any order information you provide to us on our Sites will be transmitted using a secure connection, if your Web browser cannot support this level of security, you will not be able to order products through our Sites. The most recent versions of Netscape Navigator™ and Microsoft Internet Explorer® can support a secure connection and can be downloaded for free from the Netscape and Microsoft website respectively.

No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure, The Home Depot cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us on our Sites.

**Who We Are**

The Home Depot is comprised of a family of companies and divisions brought together to provide you with a full suite of home or office improvement products and services.

**How to Contact Us**

We want to assure you that The Home Depot is dedicated to protecting your privacy.

You can contact us or otherwise communicate your privacy concerns by:

  * calling us at 1-800-553-3199
  * faxing us at 1-877-496-9470
  * e-mailing us at customercare@homedepot.com
  * accessing your registration information on our Sites
  * registering or changing your privacy preferences at www.homedepot.com/privacypreferences
  * writing us at the address below (please include your e-mail address and phone number with your correspondence along with the information needed to support your request):

For residents of the United States, Mexico and other countries: The Home Depot, Inc. Attention: Privacy Official Customer Care 2455 Paces Ferry Road Atlanta, GA 30339-4024 | For residents of Canada: The Home Depot of Canada Inc. Attention: Privacy Official 900-1 Concorde Gate Toronto, Ontario M3C 4H9  
---|---  
  
**Changes to the Privacy and Security Statement**

To help you track the changes to our Privacy and Security Statement, a history of material changes to our Privacy and Security Statement will be noted here, beginning with changes published after January 1, 2004.

October 27, 2004: Revised to identify the The Home Depot companies covered by this Privacy Statement and to add a new method for registering or changing your marketing preferences and opt-out information.

November 1, 2005: Added "Data Sharing for Catalog Mailings" under the Disclosure of Personal Information section. A Data Sharing section has also been added to the privacy preferences page where individuals can opt-out of data sharing. This change applies only to catalog purchases.

August 17, 2007: [Click here](http://www.homedepot.com/hdus/en_US/DTCCOM/HomePage/Customer_Support/Privacy_Security/Docs/The_Home_Depot_Inc_Priv_and_Sec_Stmt_Aug_2007_v3.pdf) to view a redlined version of the privacy policy for changes made on August 16, 2007.

May 6, 2010: Revised to provide information related to online advertising.

Copyright © 2010 Homer TLC, Inc. All Rights Reserved. The Home Depot is a registered trademark of Homer TLC, Inc.

Pour la version française de la Déclaration sur la sécurité et la confidentialité.

_Last updated: May 2010_
